A Guide to the Records of the Rotary Club of Arlington, 1946-1995
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Records of the Rotary Club of Arlington, 1946-1995
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 136
4 boxes.
Rotary Club of Arlington
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Tom Brannan, member of the Arlington Rotary Club, in August of 2002.
Historical Information
Chartered on July 4, 1929, the Arlington Rotary Club is an active community organization made up of local business and professional leaders and is part of Rotary International. This larger entity is a worldwide organization, consisting of over 31,000 local clubs in 166 countries. Rotary International is dedicated to service and encourages its members to "address various community and international service needs and to promote peace and understanding throughout the world."
Scope and Content
RG 136 is made up entirely of textual materials. The bulk of the materials consist of weekly club newsletters sent out to members. The contents of these newsletters include, but are not limited to, the following: reporting on a previous week's proceedings, announcing the agenda for the next meeting, detailing upcoming club-sponsored events, making general announcements about members (i.e., birthdays, accomplishments, or significant milestones).
RG 136 also contains a very small amount of miscellaneous textual items, such as some correspondence, membership lists, and newspaper clippings. The collection is a total of 1.75 linear feet and ranges in date from 1946 through 1967 and from 1985 through 1995.
Arrangement
RG 136 consists of two series. Series 1, Newsletters, is broken down into two subseries based on date. Subseries 1 contains those newsletters from 1946 through 1967 and is arranged according to volume number, in this case Volumes #9 through #35. Each volume usually begins in early July and ends in late June of the next year. This Volume/Number structure remains generally consistent. However, there are discrepancies within the system, which are listed here:
Volume 24 begins on July 7, 1960 (No. 1) and ends on December 22, 1960 (No. 24).
Volume 25 starts on December 29, 1960 (No. 25) and continues on through June 22, 1961 (No. 50).
Volume 27 starts on July 5, 1962 (No. 1) and ends on November 1, 1962 (No. 16).
Volume 28 consists of only one issue for July 19, 1962.
Volume 29 begins on July 27, 1962 (No. 3) and abruptly concludes on August 16, 1962 (No. 6).
Volume 30 commences on November 8, 1962 (No. 17) and finishes on June 27, 1963 (No. 47).
In Subseries 2, the newsletters start in 1985 and continue through 1995. Efforts to continue using volume and issue numbers stop in 1986. Therefore, these newsletters are arranged according to the calendar year, starting in January and ending in December. In addition, it should be noted that for both subseries, there are gaps where individual issues are missing.
Series 2, Miscellaneous Administrative Records, consists of correspondence, membership directories and phone lists, newspaper clippings, notes detailing the plans for an upcoming event, and blank newsletter letterhead.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
The records of other local Arlington chapters of national or international service groups can be found in RG 119, Optimists Club of Arlington Records, RG 102, Records of the Arlington Kiwanis Club, RG 197, South Arlington Kiwanis Club Records, and RG 146, Records of the Arlington Sunrise Lions Club.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Clubs.; Arlington (Va.); Arlington County (Va.)
Contents List
- Newsletters, 1946-1995
  - 1946-1967
    - Volume 9, No. 32 (February 7, 1946) - Volume 9, No. 52 (June 27, 1946) (Box 1)
    - Volume 10, No. 1 (July 3, 1947) - Volume 10, No. 52 (June 26, 1947) (Box 1)
    - Volume 10, No. 1 (July 3, 1947) - Volume 10, No. 52 (June 26, 1947) (Box 1)
    - Volume 11, No. 1 (July 3, 1946) - Volume 11, No. 48 (June 17, 1948) (Box 1)
    - Volume 12, No. 1 (July 8, 1948) - Volume 12, No. 49 (June 30, 1949) (Box 1)
    - Volume 13, No. 1 (July 7, 1949) - Volume 13, No. 49 (June 22, 1950) (Box 1)
    - Volume 14, No. 2 (July 13, 1950) - Volume 14, No. 52 (June 28, 1951) (Box 1)
    - Volume 15, No. 1 (July 15, 1951) - Volume 15, No. 51 (June 26, 1952) (Box 2)
    - Volume 16, No. 2 (July 10, 1952) - Volume 16, No. 44 (May 21, 1953) (Box 2)
    - Volume 17, No. 6 (August 6, 1953) - Volume 17, No. 51 (June 24, 1954) (Box 2)
    - Volume 18, No. 1 (July 1, 1954) - Volume 18, No. 52 (June 30, 1955) (Box 2)
    - Volume 19, No. 1 (July 7, 1955) - Volume 19, No. 50 (June 28, 1956) (Box 2)
    - Volume 20, No. 1 (July 5, 1956) - Volume 20, No. 41 (April 25, 1957) (Box 2)
    - Volume 21, No. 2 (July 11, 1957) - Volume 21, No. 51 (June 26, 1958) (Box 2)
    - Volume 22, No. 2 (July 10, 1958) - Volume 22, No. 44 (June 11, 1959) (Box 3)
    - Volume 23, No. 6 (August 6, 1959) - Volume 23, No. 47 (June 30, 1960) (Box 3)
    - Volume 24, No. 1 (July 7, 1960) - Volume 24, No. 24 (December 22, 1960) (Box 3)
    - Volume 25, No. 25 (December 29, 1960) - Volume 25, No. 50 (June 22, 1961) (Box 3)
    - Volume 26, No. 1 (July 6, 1961) - Volume 26, No. 51 (June 28, 1962) (Box 3)
    - Volume 27, No. 1 (July 5, 1962) - Volume 27, No. 16 (November 1, 1962) (Box 3)
    - Volume 28, No. 2 (July 19, 1962) (Box 3)
    - Volume 29, No. 3 (July 27, 1962) - Volume 29, No. 6 (August 16, 1962) (Box 3)
    - Volume 30, No. 17 (November 8, 1962) - Volume 30, No. 47 (June 27, 1963) (Box 3)
    - Volume 31, No. 1 (July 11, 1963) - Volume 31, No. 45 (June 4, 1964) (Box 3)
    - Volume 32, No. 2 (July 9, 1964) - Volume 32, No. 50 (June 24, 1965) (Box 3)
    - Volume 33, No. 1 (July 1, 1965) - Volume 33, No. 28 (January 13, 1966) (Box 3)
    - Volume 34, No. 30 (January 27, 1966) - Volume 34, No. 51 (June 30, 1966) (Box 3)
    - Volume 35, No. 1 (July 7, 1966) - Volume 35, No. 51 (June 29, 1967) (Box 3)
  - 1985-1995
    - Volume 52, No. 29 (January 24, 1985) - Volume 57, No. 25 (December 26, 1985) (Box 4)
    - Volume 58, No. 1 (January 2, 1986)-December 28, 1986 (Box 4)
    - January 8, 1987-December 31, 1987 (Box 4)
    - January 7, 1988-December 29, 1988 (Box 4)
    - January 5, 1989-December 14, 1989 (Box 4)
    - January 4, 1990-December 27, 1990 (Box 4)
    - January 3, 1991-December 19, 1991 (Box 4)
    - January 9, 1992-December 17, 1992 (Box 4)
    - January 7, 1993-ca. December 1993 (Box 4)
    - January 13, 1994-December 22, 1994 (Box 4)
    - January 12, 1995-June 8, 1995 (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous Administrative Records, 1990-1995
  - Membership Directories and Phone Lists, ca. 1992-1995 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, ca. 1990-1994 (Box 4)
  - Notes about Rotary Family Picnic, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Newsletter (i.e. background infomration) File (Box 4)